Guide to the Institute of Pacific Relations Records
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Part IV: McCarran Committee Files
  - Part IV.2: Releases
    - Statement by Swope, Gerard, 1951 October 9 (Box 377)
    - Facts and Fiction about the Institute of Pacific Relations, 1951 October 10 (Box 377)
    - Files in Frederick V. Field basement re: Statement by W.L. Holland, 1951 October 11 (Box 377)
    - Institute of Pacific Relations Members and Subscribers, 1951 October 19 (Box 377)
    - Lattimore, Owen to Holland, W.L., 1951 October 19 (Box 377)
    - New York Times Editorial--Institute of Pacific Relations Inquiry, 1951 October 25 (Box 377)
    - Malin, Patrick M. To Senator Pat McCarran, 1951 October 26 (Box 377)
    - Comment on Freda Utley's Allegations "by Owen Lattimore, 1951 November (Box 377)
    - Editorial in the Minneapolis Star, 1951 November 10 (Box 377)
    - William L. Holland to New York Times re: Richard Walker's letter, 1951 November 13 (Box 377)
    - Swope, Gerard to Pacific Council, 1952 January 11 (Box 377)
    - McCarthy, Joseph versus the State Department by Hornell Hart, 1952 February 4 (Box 377)
    - Statement "by Owen Lattimore presented at his hearing, 1952 February 26 (Box 377)
    - Letter to Pat McCarran "by Tomohiko Ushiba, 1952 February 29 (Box 377)
    - New York Times Editorial, 1952 March 1 (Box 378)
    - Letter to Pat McCarran by Kinkazu Saionji, 1952 March 4 (Box 378)
    - Statement by Gerard Swope at the annual meeting of the Board of Trustees, 1952 March 18 (Box 378)
    - Some comments and Replies to Allegations, 1952 March 19 (Box 378)
    - Statement by John K. Fairbank for the Internal Security Subcommittee of the Senate Judiciary, 1952 March 19 (Box 378)
    - Statement by Jerome D. Greene, 1952 March 19 (Box 378)
    - Statement by William W, Lockwood, 1952 March 19 (Box 378)
    - Statement on the Institute of Pacific Relations, 1952 March 19 (Box 378)
    - Boston Herald Letter re: Former chairman defends Institute of Pacific Relations, 1952 March 23 (Box 378)
    - Philadelphia Evening Bulletin re: 100,000.00 Fiasco, 1952 March 26 (Box 378)
    - Excerpt from the Roosevelt Torch, 1952 March 31 (Box 378)
    - Statement by T.A. Bisson, 1952 April 2 (Box 378)
    - Richard L. Walker to William Holland, 1952 April 7 (Box 378)
    - William Holland to Richard L. Walker, 1952 April 8 (Box 378)
    - Some replies to Richard L. Walker's Article, 1952 April 14 (Box 378)
    - Letter to American Institute of Pacific Relations by William L. Holland, 1952 April 15 (Box 378)
    - Letter to Pat McCarran by T.A. Bisson, 1952 April 16 (Box 378)
    - William W. Lockwood to Richard L. Walker, 1952 April 23 (Box 378)
    - Reply to Peter Tiereck by William L. Holland, 1952 April 28 (Box 378)
    - Owen Lattimore to Richard L. Walker, 1952 April 29 (Box 378)
    - Testimony before the Senate Subcommittee by Edward C. Carter, 1952 May 1 (Box 378)
    - Affidavit by Hilda Austern (Ray), 1952 May 5 (Box 378)
    - List of pamphlets issued by American Institute of Pacific Relations, 1952 June 13 (Box 378)
    - Edward C. Carter letter to Carl L. Alsberg, 1952 June 22 (Box 378)
    - Commenting on report of Senate Subcommittee on Internal Security by William L. Holland, 1952 July 2 (Box 378)
    - Except from report of the Senate Judiciary Subcommittee on Internal Security concerning the Institute of Pacific Relations – Conclusions, 1952 July 2 (Box 378)
    - New commentary by Eric Sevareid - CBS Radio, 1952 July 2 (Box 378)
    - Owen Lattimore Release, 1952 July 2 (Box 378)
    - Speech by Senator Pat McCarran in connection with a report of the Internal Security Subcommittee, 1952 July 2 (Box 378)
    - Editorial from the Washington Post, 1952 July 4 (Box 378)
    - Article - Honolulu Advertiser, 1952 July 5 (Box 378)
    - Memorandum on alleged false testimony, 1952 July 12 (Box 378)
    - Gerard Swope to the Trustees of the American Institute of Pacific Relations, 1952 July 29 (Box 378)
    - Letter by William L. Holland to those who submitted letters commenting on the work of the American Institute of Pacific Relations, 1952 July 31 (Box 378)
    - Institute of Pacific Relations: A Probe in Prospective, 1952 August 4 (Box 378)
    - Excerpts from testimony "by Mr. Dollard and Mr. Leffingwell, 1952 December 2 (Box 378)
    - Excerpts from testimony by Mrs. Straight, 1952 December 5 (Box 378)
    - Excerpts from testimony by Mr. Rusk, 1952 December 9 (Box 378)
    - Owen Lattimore the Scholar, 1953 (Box 378)
    - Preliminary Statement, 1953 February 26 (Box 378)
    - Address before the Commonwealth Club of San Francisco by Harold H. Fisher, 1953 February 27 (Box 378)
    - Questionnaire - To members and friends of the Institute of Pacific Relations, 1953 March 31 (Box 378)
    - Opinion of Judge Luther W. Youngdahl, 1953 May 2 (Box 378)
    - International Institute of Pacific Relations refutes charges, Undated (Box 379)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Undated-1946 (Box 379)
      - 1947-1951 (Box 379)
      - 1951-1952 (Box 379)
      - 1953-1955 (Box 379)
  - Part IV.3: Printed Materials
    - Institute of Pacific Relations Materials re: McCarran Committee Investigation (Box 380-381)
    - Clippings (Box 380)
    - Books (Box 381)
- Part V: Financial Records
  (Boxes 382-439)
  - Part V.1: General Correspondence
    (re: IPR publications and memos. Litigations re: Tax Exemption status. Rockefeller Foundation grants, request for grants and payments, discrepancies and appropriations, Contracts, Lease, etc.)
    - General Correspondence
      - Board of Trustees-List AIPR letter of April 9 and Auditors Report (Box 382)
      - RE: IPR Publications
        - A-J (Box 382)
        - K-T (Box 382)
        - U-Z (Box 382)
    - Litigations RE: Tax Exemption Status (Box 382)
    - Memorandum RE: IPR Publications (Box 382)
    - Rockefeller Foundation
      - Applications for Grants (Box 382)
      - Applications for Payment and Resolutions (Box 382)
      - Appropriations, 1929-1939 (Box 382)
      - Day, Edmund E. (Box 382)
      - Financial Statement (Box 382)
      - Fosdick, Raymond B. (Box 382)
      - List of Payments to IPR from J.D. Rockefeller, Laura S. Rockefeller Memorial and the Rockefeller Foundation through 1931 Summary of Rockefeller Foundation Grants with letters conveying the Resolutions (Box 382)
      - Mason, Dr. May (Box 382)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 382)
      - Young Woman Christian Association RE: IPR Contracts, Lease, etc. (Box 382)
    - Tax Exemption
      - American Institute of Pacific Relations
        - Annual Report (Box 383)
        - By-Laws (Box 383)
        - Certificate of Incorporation (Box 383)
        - Copies of Letters (Box 383)
        - Distribution of Letters (2 Folders) (Box 383)
        - Hawkins, Delafield, Wood and Treasury, also J.M. Murphy to Treasury (Box 383)
        - Holland, William L. covering letter to Trustees sent with memo, 1953 August 26 (Box 383)
        - Kades letter to Commissioner of Internal Revenue Service, 1953 August 18 (Box 383)
        - New York City and State (Box 383)
        - New York City Sales (Box 383)
        - New York State and Federal Unemployment Insurance (Box 383)
        - Social Security Assessment Documents, 1955 (Box 383)
        - Tax Case (Box 384)
        - Tax Case Herbert S. Little and Benjamin Kizer, 1958 (Box 384)
        - Tax Rulings (U.S. Treasury Dept.) (Box 384)
        - Treasury Department (Box 384)
      - American Institute of Pacific Relations versus United Sates of America
        - Withholding Tax Statement (Box 384)
        - Exhibit Printed Material (Box 384)
  - Part V.2: Financial statements and reports, foundation support records
    These records are arranged chronologically.
    - Carnegie Endowment--General (2 Folders), Undated (Box 385)
    - Rosenwald, Julius. Rand--Appeal and Finance, Undated (Box 385)
    - Rockefeller Foundation Appeal Letters--Laura Spelman, Undated (Box 385)
    - Carnegie Endowment--General, 1911-1933 (Box 385)
    - Financial Statements, 1925-1926 (Box 385)
    - Financial. Statements--Reconciliation, 1925-1933 (Box 385)
    - Price Waterhouse Company--Auditors Report, 1926, 1934 (Box 385)
    - Rockefeller Foundation Appeal Letters--Laura Spelman-E.C. Carter, 1926 (Box 385)
    - Rosenwald., Julius Fund--Appeals and Finance, 1926 (Box 385)
    - Rockefeller Foundation Appeal Letters--Laura Spelman-E.C. Carter, 1927 (Box 385)
    - Carnegie Endowment--Finch, George A., 1928-1930 (Box 385)
    - Financial. Statements and Reports, 1928 (Box 385)
    - Rockefeller Foundation Appeal Letters--Financial Statements, 1928 (Box 385)
    - Rockefeller-Foundation Appeal Letters--Laura Spelman-E.C. Carter, 1928 (Box 385)
    - American Council--Financial Statements--Treasury Report, 1928-1932 (Box 385)
    - American Council--Financial Statements and Reports, 1929 (Box 385)
    - AIPR--Report on Exam of Cash Records, 1929-1944 (Box 385)
    - American Council-Financial Statements and Reports, 1930 (Box 385)
    - Rosenwald, Julius Fund--Appeal and Finance, 1930 (Box 385)
    - American Council--Financial Statements and Reports--General (2 Folders), 1931 (Box 385)
    - Carnegie Endowment--Finch, George A., 1931 (Box 385)
    - American Council--Financial Sate and Reports, 1931 (Box 385)
    - Rockefeller Foundation Appeal Letters--Arthur W. Packard, 1931 (Box 385)
    - Rosenwald, Julius-Fund--Appeals and Finance, 1931 (Box 385)
    - Rockefeller Foundation Appeal Letters
      - John D. Rockefeller, Jr,, 1931 January 31 (Box 385)
      - Dr. Max Mason, 1931 April 6 (Box 385)
    - American Council-Financial Statements and Reports--General (2 Folders), 1932 (Box 386)
    - Carnegie Endowment, 1932
      - Butler, Nicholas-Murray (Box 386)
      - Finch, George A. (Box 386)
    - Financial Statements, 1932
      - List of contributions Monthly Statement (Box 386)
      - Report on Exam of Cash Records (Box 386)
    - Financial Statements and Reports--General (2 Folders), 1932 (Box 386)
    - Rockefeller, John D., Jr.--Gift, 1932 (Box 386)
    - Rockefeller Foundation Appeal Letters--Dr. Max Mason Stabilization Appeal, 1932 (Box 386)
    - Rosenwald, Julius-Fund--Appeals and Finance, 1932 (Box 386)
    - Carnegie Endowment--Keppel, Frederick P., 1933 (Box 386)
    - American Council-Financial Statements, 1933
      - General (Box 386)
      - List of Contributions Monthly Statement (Box 386)
      - Report on Exam of Cash Records (Box 386)
    - Rockefeller Foundation Appeal Letters--Mark Jones, 1933 (Box 386)
    - Rosenwald, Julius Fund--Appeals and Finance, 1933 (Box 386)
    - American Council--Financial Statements, 1933 January 1-November 13 (Box 386)
    - Carnegie Endowment
      - Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1933 February 16 (Box 386)
      - Finch, George A., 1933 September 25 (Box 386)
    - Rockefeller Foundation Appeal Letters
      - Arthur Packard, 1933 October 16 (Box 386)
      - Dr. Max Mason, 1933 November 14 (Box 386)
    - Carnegie Endowment, 1934
      - General (Box 386)
      - Keppel, Frederick P. (Box 386)
    - Financial Statements, 1934
      - General (Box 386)
      - List of Contributions Monthly Statement (Box 386)
      - Report on Exam of Cash Records (Box 386)
    - Rockefeller Foundation--Appeal Letters, 1934
      - General (Box 386)
      - Arthur Packard (Box 386)
      - Dr. David Stevens (Box 386)
    - Rosenwald, Julius Fund--Appeals and Finance, 1934 (Box 386)
    - Payne Fund--Acknowledge Letter, 1934 (Box 386)
    - Carnegie Endowment--Finch, George A., 1934 September 24 (Box 386)
    - American Council-Financial Statements and Reports--General (2 Folders), 1935 (Box 387)
    - Payne Fund, 1935 (Box 387)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1935
      - Davison Fund (Box 387)
      - Director of Davison Fund (Box 387)
      - General Purposes (Box 387)
      - Stevens, Dr. David (Box 387)
      - Appeals and Finance (Box 387)
    - Carnegie Endowment--Finch, George A., 1935 September 10 (Box 387)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1935 November 11
      - Letter of Dr. Max Mason (Box 387)
      - Letter to Packard, Arthur W. (Box 387)
    - China, 1935-1938 (Box 387)
    - American Council
      - Minutes of Meeting, 1935-1938 (Box 387)
      - Financial Statements, 1936 (Box 387)
      - Financial Statements and Reports, 1936 (Box 387)
    - Carnegie Endowment--General Purposes, 1936 (Box 387)
    - Yosemite Conference Pictures, 1936 (Box 387)
    - Finch, George A., 1936 July 7 (Box 387)
    - Yosemite Conference Follow-up, 1936-1937 (Box 387)
    - USSR, 1936-1940 (Box 387)
    - American Council--Financial Statements and Reports (2 Folders), 1937 (Box 388)
    - Carnegie Endowment--General Purposes, 1937 (Box 388)
    - Pacific Council--Financial Statements and Reports, 1937 (Box 388)
    - Carnegie Endowment--Finch, George A., 1937 January 27 (Box 388)
    - American Council
      - Minutes of Annual Meeting, 1937 December 17 (Box 388)
      - Executive Committee Annual Meeting, 1937-1938 (Box 388)
    - Carnegie Endowment--Keppel, Frederick P., 1937-1939 (Box 388)
    - American Council, 1938
      - Executive Committee Meeting and Minutes (Box 388)
      - Financial Statements and Reports (Box 388)
      - Nomination for Membership (Box 388)
    - Carnegie Endowment, 1938
      - Finch George A. (Box 388)
      - General Purposes (Box 388)
    - Pacific Council.--Financial Statements and Reports (2 Folders), 1938 (Box 388)
    - Publication Receipts, 1938 (Box 388)
    - Special Projects—Correspondence, 1938 (Box 388)
    - Rockefeller Foundation--Letter to Miss. S. Walker. 1938 November 21 (Box 388)
    - American Council, 1939
      - Financial Contribution (Box 388)
      - Financial Statements and Reports (Box 388)
    - Carnegie Endowment, 1939
      - Finch, George A. (Box 388)
      - General Purposes (Box 388)
    - Pacific Council, 1939
      - Financial Statements (Box 388)
      - Financial Statements--International Secretariat Inquiry (Box 388)
    - American Council--Executive. Committee Minutes, 1939-1941 (Box 388)
    - American Council Financial Statements and Reports (2 Folders), 1940 (Box 388)
    - American Russian Institute--Auditor’s Report, 1940 (Box 390)
    - Pacific Council, 1940
      - Financial Statements and Report--International Secretariat Inquiry (Box 390)
      - Receipts from Publications (Box 390)
    - Rockefeller Foundation
      - General Purposes, 1940 (Box 390)
      - Letter to Dr. J.H. Willits, 1940 (Box 390)
      - Letter to Dr. J.H. Willits, 1940 November 6 (Box 390)
    - Special Projects—Correspondence, 1940-1942 (Box 390)
    - American Council, 1941
      - Board of Trustees Meeting (Box 390)
      - Financial Statements and Reports (Box 390)
    - Pacific Council, 1941
      - Financial Statements and Reports (Box 390)
      - Financial Statements--International Secretariat Inquiry (Box 390)
      - Receipts form Publications (Box 390)
    - Rockefeller-Foundation--General Purposes, 1941 (Box 390)
    - Pacific Council--Letter to Dr. Frederick P. Keppel, 1941 February 27 (Box 390)
    - American Council--Executive Committee Minutes, 1941-1942 (Box 390)
    - Broek, ProJ.O.M., 1941-1942 (Box 390)
    - Carnegie Project, 1941-1942 (Box 390)
    - American Council, 1942
      - Chicago (Box 390)
      - Financial Statements and Reports (Box 390)
      - Publications Fund (Box 390)
      - Publications Fund--Summary Reports (Box 390)
      - Statements of Receipts and Expenditures (Box 390)
      - Washington (Box 391)
    - Pacific Council, 1942
      - Financial Statements (Box 391)
      - Financial Statements--International Secretariat Inquiry (Box 391)
    - Pacific--Receipts from Publications, 1942 (Box 391)
    - Rockefeller Foundation
      - Letter to Dr. Joseph H. Willits, 1942 (Box 391)
      - Letter to Dr. Joseph H. Willits, 1942 November 2 (Box 391)
    - Special Projects, 1942-1943 (Box 391)
    - American Council, 1943
      - Chicago (Box 391)
      - Financial Statements and Reports
        - General (Box 391)
        - General Fund (Box 391)
        - General Purposes (Box 391)
        - Geographic Contributions (Box 391)
        - Monthly List of Contributions (Box 391)
        - Publication Fund (Box 391)
        - Special Project (Box 391)
      - Pacific Northwest (Box 391)
      - Publications Fund (Box 391)
    - Textbook Project, 1942-1947 (Box 391)
    - American Council, 1943
      - San Francisco Office (Box 392)
      - Washington (Box 392)
    - Pacific Council, 1943
      - Financial Statements--International Secretariat Inquiry (Box 392)
      - Receipts from Publications (Box 392)
    - OFRRO Project, 1943 (Box 392)
    - Rockefeller Foundation--General Purposes, 1943 (Box 392)
    - Pacific Council--Letter to Arthur W. Packard, 1943 March 29 (Box 392)
    - Report on Short Wave Research, Inc., 1943 May 31 (Box 392)
    - UOPWA Contracts, 1943 (Box 392)
    - Foundation Grants, 1943-1947 (Box 392)
    - International Research Fund Authorization, 1943-1947 (Box 392)
    - American Council, 1944
      - Chicago (Box 393)
      - FEA Program (Box 393)
      - Financial Statement and Reports (Box 393)
      - General Fund (Box 393)
      - Milwaukee Chapter (Box 393)
      - Monthly List of Contributions (Box 393)
      - Publication Fund--Cumulative (Box 393)
      - Pullman-Moscow Division (Box 393)
      - Research Fund--Cumulative (Box 393)
      - San Francisco (Box 393)
      - Washington (Box 393)
    - American IPR--Hawaii Office, 1944 (Box 393)
    - Bank, 1944 (Box 393)
    - Carnegie Fund, 1944 (Box 393)
    - Pacific Council, 1944
      - General Purposes (Box 393)
      - Inquiry Account (Box 393)
      - Publication Sales (Box 393)
    - Rockefeller--Beal, G.J., 1944 (Box 393)
    - Pacific Affairs Distribution, 1944-1945 (Box 393)
    - Special Projects, 1944-1945 (Box 393)
    - Wittfogel Project, 1944-1947 (Box 393)
    - UOPWA Contracts (Books and Magazine Guild), 1944-1949 (Box 393)
    - American Council, 1945
      - Chicago (Box 394)
      - Consolidated Statement (Box 394)
      - Financial Statements and Reports (Box 394)
      - General Fund (Box 394)
      - General Fund--Cumulative Budget (Box 394)
      - Milwaukee Chapter (Box 394)
      - Monthly List of Contributions (Box 394)
      - Navy Orders (Box 394)
      - Publication Fund (Box 394)
      - Publication Fund--Cumulative (Box 394)
      - Pullman-Moscow Division (Box 394)
      - Research Fund (Box 394)
      - Research Fund--Cumulative (Box 394)
      - San Francisco Office (Box 394)
      - Seattle Office (Box 394)
      - Washington (Box 394)
    - AIPR, 1945
      - Hawaii Office (Box 394)
      - Report on Exam of Cash-Record (Box 394)
    - Pacific Council, 1945
      - Financial Statement--International Secretary Inquiry (Box 394)
      - General Purpose (Box 394)
    - Staff Meeting, 1945 (Box 394)
    - Special Project—Correspondence, 1945-1947 (Box 394)
    - Carnegie Corporation, 1945-1950 (Box 394)
    - American Council, 1946
      - Chicago (Box 395)
      - Consolidated Statement (Box 395)
      - Financial Statements and Reports (Box 395)
      - General Fund (Box 395)
      - General Purpose (Box 395)
      - Los Angeles Office (Box 395)
      - Milwaukee Chapter (Box 395)
      - Monthly List of Contributions (Box 395)
      - Publication Fund (Box 395)
      - Pullman-Moscow Division (Box 395)
      - Research Fund (Box 395)
      - Research Fund--Cumulative (Box 395)
      - San Francisco Office (Box 395)
      - Seattle Office (Box 395)
      - Washington (Box 395)
    - AIPR--Hawaii Office, 1946 (Box 396)
    - Pacific Council, 1946
      - Document Presented at Meeting (Box 396)
      - Financial Statements (Box 396)
      - Financial Statements--International Secretary Inquiry (Box 396)
      - Report of International Secretary and Chairman of International Finance Committee (Box 396)
    - Sales Office, 1946 (Box 396)
    - Broek, J.O.M, 1946 (Box 396)
    - Cost, 1946-1949 (Box 396)
    - Research, 1946-1949 (Box 396)
    - Amerasia Correspondence, 1947 (Box 396)
    - American Council, 1947
      - Chicago (Box 396)
      - Los Angeles Office (Box 396)
      - Seattle Office (Box 396)
      - Seattle Office (Yu letters) (Box 396)
      - Washington (Box 396)
      - Washington, D.C. Office (Yu letters) (Box 396)
      - San Francisco Office (Box 397)
    - AIPR, 1947
      - Consolidated Statements (Box 397)
      - Financial Statements and Reports (Box 397)
      - General Fund (Box 397)
      - Hawaii Office (Box 397)
      - Hawaii Office--Yoshi, Uchida letters (Box 397)
      - Monthly List of Contribution (Box 397)
      - Publication Fund (Box 397)
      - Research Fund (Box 397)
    - Appeal, 1947 (Box 397)
    - Chinese Language Course, 1947 (Box 397)
    - Pacific Council, 1947
      - International Research Fund (Box 397)
      - Mimeograph copies of Auditors Report (Box 397)
    - American Airlines--General Information, 1947-1949 (Box 397)
    - Borg, Dorothy, 1947-1949 (Box 397)
    - Indian-American Conference, 1947-1950 (Box 397)
    - Pullman-Moscow Office, 1947-1954 (Box 397)
    - Amerasia-Correspondence, 1948 (Box 397)
    - AIPR, 1948
      - Budget (Box 397)
      - Budget and Expenditure (Box 397)
      - Detailed Statements (Box 397)
      - Financial Statements and Reports (Box 398)
      - Hawaii Office Report (Box 398)
      - Monthly List of Contributions (Box 398)
      - Receipts and Expenditure (Box 398)
      - Receipts from Sales of Publication (Box 398)
      - Report on Exam of Cash Records (Box 398)
      - Research Fund (Box 398)
      - San Francisco Office (Box 398)
      - Seattle Office (Box 398)
      - Seattle Office (Unpaid REports)' (Box 398)
    - Annual Meeting, 1948 (Box 398)
    - Far East Survey Distribution, 1948 (Box 398)
    - International Research Fund Authorization, 1948 (Box 398)
    - Inventory, 1948 (Box 398)
    - Lane, Clayton Confidential, 1948 (Box 398)
    - Pacific Council, 1948
      - Financial Statements (Box 398)
      - PACCO Finance (Box 398)
    - Retirement Plans 1948-1949 (Box 399)
    - Annual -Reviews- of Far East, 1948-1950 (Box 399)
    - Publications, 1948-1950 (Box 399)
    - AIPR, 1949
      - Budget and Expenditure (Box 399)
      - Detailed Statement (Box 399)
      - Monthly List of Contributions (Box 399)
      - Carter, Edward C.--Dinner in his Honor (Box 399)
      - Financial Commitment (Box 399)
      - Hawaii Office
        - Correspondence (Box 399)
        - Report (Box 399)
      - Receipts and Expenditure (Box 399)
      - Receipts from Sales of Publication (Box 399)
      - Report on Exam of Cash Records- (Box 399)
      - Research Fund (Box 399)
      - San Francisco Office (Box 399)
      - Seattle Office
        - Correspondence (Box 399)
        - Report (Box 399)
    - Far East Survey Distribution, 1949 (Box 399)
    - International Research Fund Auth., 1949 (Box 399)
    - Pacific Council-Meeting Vol. I, II, III, 1949 (Box 399)
    - Corn Exchange Bank, 1948-1952 (Box 399)
    - Pacific Council--Annual-Statements, 1949-1950 (Box 399)
    - Teachers’ Annuity Insurance Assoc., 1949-1954 (Box 399)
    - American Council, 1950
      - Hawaii Office (Box 400)
        - Correspondence (Box 400)
        - Report (Box 400)
      - Seattle Office Correspondence (Box 400)
    - AIPR, 1950
      - Budget (Box 400)
      - Budget and Expenditure (Box 400)
      - Detailed Statements (Box 400)
      - Executive and Finance Committee (Box 400)
      - Financial Commitments (Box 400)
      - Monthly-List of Contribution (Box 400)
      - Receipts and Expenditure. (Box 400)
      - Receipts from Sale of Publication (Box 400)
      - Report on Exam on Cash Records (Box 400)
      - Research Fund (Box 400)
      - 25th Anniversary Committee (Box 400)
    - AIPR--Internal Revenue Code, 1950-1956 (Box 400)
    - American Council, 1951